Register to The Seymour Shifrin Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, 1943-1979; Series I; 9.4' (6 boxes)
  - Choral Works, I.E
    - [Chronicles] Chronicles, August 2, 1970.; 1 score (73 p.); 43 cm. (Box 5, Folder 44.5)
    - [Chronicles (Sketches)], 1 score ([66] p.); 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 43)
      Includes typescripts and photocopies of text in transliteration and translation with notes by Seymour Shifrin (85 sheets).
      Also includes translation of Job in pencil ([3] p.).
    - [Give ear, o ye heavens] Give ear, o ye heavens: the song of Moses, [1959].; 1 score (10 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 29)
      For chorus (SSAATTBB) and organ.
      Text adapted from Deuteronomy xxxii.
    - [Give ear o ye heavens (Sketches)], 1 score ([11] p.); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Lament for Oedipus
      See: Cantata to Sophoclean choruses.
    - [Mediaeval Latin lyric] A Mediaeval Latin lyric, 1954 Jan. 30.; 1 score ([4] p.); 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Holograph (photocopy).
      For chorus (SATB).
      Words by Ausonius, translation Helen Waddell.
    - Ode
    - [Odes of Shang] The Odes of Shang, 1962 Oct. 20.; 1 score (41 p.), bound + 1 part; 32-38 cm. (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Holograph (photocopy) with marks in red, pencil, and ink.
      For chorus (SSAATTBB), piano, and percussion.
      Translation by Ezra Pound.
      On title page: Commissioned by the Berkeley Chamber Singers.
      Includes manuscript piano part ([411 p.) in unknown hand with marks in red pencil and ink.
      Photocopy of text and score laid in.
      For special required instruments see: IX. MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS.
    - [Odes of Shang] The Odes of Shang, Oct. 20, 1962.; 1 score (41 p.); 38 cm. (Box 4, Folder 33.5)
      On container: Copyright 1974 by C.F. Peters Corporation.
    - [Odes of Shang (Sketches)], 1 score ([51] p.); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Paean
  - Unidentified Sketches, I.F
    - Unidentified Sketches, [6] p. of music; 27 cm. (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified Sketches, [26] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified Sketches, [9] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified Sketches, [6] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified Sketches, [67] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 56)
      For string quartet.
  - Sound Recordings, I.G
    Sound recordings have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings Collection in the Music Library. For further information about archival recordings relating to Seymour Shifrin, please contact the Curator of Historical Sound Recordings.
- Correspondence, 1942-1981; Series II; 2.2' (8 boxes)
  The correspondence series of the Shifrin papers includes holograph and typescript letters to Shifrin, by Shifrin and members of his family, and condolence letters to his wife, Miriam Shifrin. This series is divided into eight subseries (A-H) by subject. The subseries F (Universities) and H (Miscellaneous) are arranged chronologically within each subdivision. All other subseries (A-E and G) are arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject.
  - Family Correspondence, II.A
    - From Shifrin to others, II.A.1
      - Cambridge Savings Bank, 1966 Aug. 22; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Graffeots Coffee House, 1966-1968; 8 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - P.G.C. Hajenius, 1965-1968; 8 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
        Includes invoices.
      - Parents, 1955 Jan. 21; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Vanguard Investments, 1967 Apr. 24; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - By other family members, II.A.2
      - Miriam Shifrin, 1966-1968; 6 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Ted Shifrin, 1964-1965; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - To Miriam Shifrin, II.A.3
      - Basart, Bob and Ann, 1979 Oct. 29; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Birnbaum, Leila, 1979 Sep. 27; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Breitman, David, 1979 Dec. 20; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Cohen, Naomi, 1979 Oct. 21; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Curtis, Alan, 1979 Oct. 9; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Durant, Doug, 1979 Oct. 18; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Edwards family, 1979 Sep. 29; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Fink family, 1979 Sep. 28; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Halpern, Marty and Nancy, 1979 Oct. 5; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Imbrie, Andrew, 1979 Sep. 30; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Pope, Conrad, 1979 Oct. 3; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Preble, Ellie, 1979 Dec. 28; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Shapiro, Lois, 1979 Oct. 1; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Shapiro, Jim, 1979 Sep. 28; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Thomas, John P., 1979 Oct. 8; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Treibitz, C. Howard, 1979 Oct.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Weingrod, Bracha, 1979 Oct. 23; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Weingrod, Alex, 1979 Oct. 23; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Others to Shifrin, II.B
    - Alderman, Jean Poole, 1979 Mar. 7; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Annicchiarico, Michael, 1979 Mar. 28; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Arrigo, Girolamo, 1965 Feb. 12; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Asarnow, Elliot, 1976-1978; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Babbitt, Milton, 1958-1976; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Barkin, Elaine, 1976-1977; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Batstone, Phil, 1973-1974; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Beardslee, Bethany, 1976 Feb. 28; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Beloof, Robert, 1963-1966; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Berger, Arthur, 1958-1979; 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Berko, Stephan, 1976 Oct.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Berry, Wallace, 1970 Aug. 19; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Black, Robert, 1977-1979; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Blaustein, Susan, 1978-1979; 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Boone, Charles, 1978 Oct. 16; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Boretz, Benjamin, 1959-1977; 13 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Boros, David John, 1966-1972; 17 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Boyden, David, 1962-1970; 6 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Boykan, Martin, 1964-1972; 10 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Brandeis colleagues and students, [1979]; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Brendel, Alfred, 1952-1977; 15 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Brody, Martin, 1978 Nov. 15; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Carnovsky, Gertrude, 1976 Oct. 5; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chaitkin, David, 1968-1978; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chanes, J. C., 1977 Jun.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Child, Peter, 1978 Jan. 30; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cohen, Edward, 1964-1977; 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cohen, Marjorie Merriman, no year Aug. 9; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Composition class, Brandeis, [1979]; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cone, Edward T., 1968-1970; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cook, Peter A., 1975-1978; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Copland, Aaron, 1956-1971; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Copley, Norma, 1962 Jan. 24; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Curtis, Alan, 1966-1970; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dahl, Ingolf, 1963-1964; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1963-1968; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Danenberg, Emil, 1966 Mar. 13; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Dashow, James, 1960-1974; 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Curtis W., 1978 Jan. 24-Feb. 1; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - DeGaetani, Jan, 1968 May 15; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - DeSomery, Gene, 1979 Mar. 26; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - deVaron, Lorna Cooke, 1973-1977; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Durant, Doug, 1979 Apr. 4; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Durr, Sue, 1966-1979; 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Edwards, George, 1974-1979; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Einem, Gottfried von, 1957; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Elkus, Elizabeth, 1962-1979; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Elston, Arnold, 1967-1970; 11 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Evans, David, 1978 Feb. 1; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Farnsworth, Helen, 1978 Jun. 8; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Felciano, Richard, 1964 Aug. 2; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fink, Barbara, 1974-1979; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Finney, Ross Lee, 1964 Nov. 10; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fisher, George, 1972-1979; 25 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fisher, Stephen, 1975 Sep. 4; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Foley, Hoag and Eliot, 1967 Jun. 22; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Forte, Allen, 1960 Oct. 3; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fortner, Jack, 1970 Feb. 3; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Frankenstein, Alfred, 1965 Sep. 11; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fred - Brandeis custodian, no date; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fromm, Paul, 1976 Sep. 30; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Gaburo, Kenneth, 1969; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Gamer, Carlton, 1976 Dec. 23; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Goldberg, Robert C., 1969-1973; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Grotrian Piano Co., 1978 Oct. 13; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hagerty, Mark, 1975-1976; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Halpern, Marty, 1965 Sep. 19; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Hamer, Jan, 1974-1978; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Harbison, John, 1966-1978; 17 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Donald, 1974 Feb. 25; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Helps, Robert, 1968-1973; 13 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hillyer, Raphael, 1963 Oct. 27; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hochbaum, Tama, no date; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hoffman, Richard, 1964 Mar. 1; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Howe, Winifred, 1977 Dec.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hyatt, Iva Dee, no date; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Imbrie, Andrew W., 1969-1979; 13 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Ingham, Michael, 1978 Mar. 17; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Jacobson, Norman, 1966-1975; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - James, Thomas, 1978; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kalischer, Clemens, 1977 May 17; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kass, Sue, 1978-1979; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kirchner, Leon, 1963-1979; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kohn, Karl, 1964-1973; 8 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kolisch, Rudolph, 1960-1964; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kronenberger, Louis, no year Jun. 28; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Lansky, Paul, 1974 Oct. 26-Dec. 15; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lawton, David, 1968 Oct. 28; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - LeFanu, Nicola, 1972-1976; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lerdahl, Fred, 1968-1971; 9 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lewin, David, 1968 Sep. 23; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lewis, D.F., 1973 Dec. 7; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - London, Fires of, 1972-1978; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Luening, Otto, 1952-1972; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - McElroy, Pat, 1969 Nov. 3; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - McGuire, Jack, 1966-1971; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mandel, Marc, 1972 Aug. 24; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mannheimer, Frank, 1963-1971; 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Martirano, Salvatore, 1963-1965; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mazur, Michael, no date; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Meier, Gustav and Shirley, 1957-1968; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Meyer, Leonard B., 1969 May 13; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Miles, Josephine, 1967-1968; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Milhaud, Darius, 1952-1961; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Millay Colony, The, 1977-1978; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Miller, Robert, 1976 Jul. 15-27; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mitchell, William, 1961 Feb. 21; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mitchell, Fred and Greta, 1967-1978; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Monod, Jacques, 1964-1978; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Moore, Douglas, 1950 Jun. 26; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Newcomb, Anthony, no date; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Nin-Culmell, Joaquín, 1952-1965; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Novack, Susan, 1963 Nov. 22; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Olesen, James, 1979 Feb. 1; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Oppens, Kurt H., 1968 May 22; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Oppens, Ursula, 1977 Jan. 19; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Osborne, Selden, 1963-1970; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Papaioanna, John, 1961 Dec.; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Perle, George, no year Jan. 26; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Petersen, Wayne, 1969-1970; 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Petray, Marjorie, 1967 Aug. 28; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Petrobelli, Pier Luigi, no date; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Pelatowski, Glo, no year Jan. 23; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Polikoff, Max, 1960; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Polk, Keith, 1965 Oct. 23; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Raimondi, Matthew, 1962-1968; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Rifkin, Joshua, no year Jun. 19; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Salkind, Milton and Peggy, 1960-1970; 3 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schuman, William, 1942-1978; 71 items. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schwartz, Nathan, 1966-1975; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sentrie family, no year Feb. 11; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Senturia, Michael C., 1968-1969; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sessions, Roger, 1959-1976; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Shapero, Harold, 1966 May 17; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Shapey, Ralph, 1964-1966; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Shapiro, Jim, 1977 Oct. 2; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sheinkman, Mordechai and Shoshana, 1957; 9 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sims, Ezra, 1979 Mar. 31; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sir, Neil, 1966 Jun. 19-Aug. 25; 3 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Spies, Claudio, 1965-1979; 59 items. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Starr, Helen, 1968 Nov. 29; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Stephani, Gino, 1964 Apr. 1-May 30; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Stein, Leonard, 1963 Jan. 30-Aug. 10; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Steinberg, Michael, 1976 Apr. 30-Dec. 2; 3 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1959 Jan. 29; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Includes music written for Ted Shifrin.
    - Suben, Joel, 1972-1978; 6 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Swackhammer, John, 1966-1978; 9 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Swift, Richard, 1975 Mar. 31-Apr. 29; 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Thomas, John, 1962-1979; 9 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Treitler, Leo, 1964-1979; 10 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Verschoor, Inald and Sukey Barnhart, 1972; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Weiner, Yehudi, 1961 Oct. 25; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Weingrod, Bracha, no date; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Weitzner, Richard, 1974 Jun. 14; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Wellesley College, 1979 Mar. 28; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Telegram.
    - Wernick, Richard, 1968 Dec. 29; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Williams, Howard, no date; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Wilson, George B., 1964-1973; 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Winkler, Peter, 1976 Oct. 29; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Zonn, Paul, 1969 Nov. 30; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Deanna, Steve, Allen, Tama (Hochbaum?), 1979; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, II.C
    - American Composers' Alliance, 1958-1981; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes contracts.
    - Associated Music Publishers, Inc., 1966 Apr. 25-May 9; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bay Area Educational Television Association, 1962 Oct.-Nov.; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Boelke-Bomart, Inc., 1975-1978; 7 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Boosey & Hawkes Artists Bureau, Inc., 1942 Dec. 11; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bote & Book, 1960-1965; 10 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - College Music Society, 1970 Jan. 21; 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes draft of a paper by Seymour Shifrin.
    - Hill, Barlow, Goodale & Adams, 1963 May 13; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Little, Brown & Co., 1967 Jan. 24-25; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - MacMillan Company, 1963 Dec. 5-19; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes copies.
    - Edward B. Marks Music Corp., 1961-1968; 5 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Music Forum, Columbia University Press, 1964 Oct. 13-Nov. 20; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - New Directions, 1963 Apr. 15; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Perspectives of New Music, 1962-1978; 11 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - C.F. Peters Corporation, 1957-1981; 61 items. (Box 13, Folder 5-9)
      Includes contracts and replies from Seymour Shifrin.
    - Theodore Presser, 1970-1981; 6 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - A.P. Watt & Son, 1960 Aug. 19-23; 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Commissions and Awards, II.D
    - Aeolian Chamber Players, 1964-1965; 4 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Includes clipping.
    - American International Music Fund, 1970-192; 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Congregation Emanu-El, 1968-1977; 5 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - William and Noma Copley Foundation, 1961 Feb. 16-Mar. 7; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Fine Arts Quartet, 1956-1967; 12 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Includes replies from Seymour Shifrin.
    - Fromm Music Foundation, 1964 Oct. 1-13; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1956-1959; 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Includes budget.
    - University of Illinois String Research Project, 1967-1972; 22 items. (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Includes response by Seymour Shifrin and contracts.
    - Juilliard School, 1954 Apr. 6; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Koussevitzky Music Foundation, 1962 Oct. 15; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - University of Massachusetts, 1968 Jul. 17; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - University of Michigan, 1963-1972; 10 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1957 Mar. 6-May 22; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Walter W. Naumberg Foundation, Inc., 1970-1972; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Princeton University, 1953 Nov. 9-Dec. 22; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Pro Arte Quartett University of Wisconsin, 1968-1974; 9 items. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - San Francisco Chamber Music Society, 1973-1978; 6 items. (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Includes response by Seymour Shifrin.
    - Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1972 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Performers and Various Musical Organizations, II.E
    - American Choral Foundation, Inc., 1961-1966; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - American Composers Alliance, 1976 Apr. 20-Sep. 27; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - American Music Center, Inc., 1966 Apr. 28; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - American Society of University Composers, 1966 Jan. 6; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Berkeley Chamber Singers, 1964 Aug. 3; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Brandeis University, 1959-1962; 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Broadcast Music, Inc., 1958-1959; 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - University of California, Santa Barbara, 1977 Feb. 27; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Carleton College, 1969 Dec. 30; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Chalkin, Jack, 1962 Jun. 14-Jul. 10; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Da Capo Chamber Players, 1974 Jun. 7; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Fromm Music Foundation, 1953-1974; 19 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Group for Contemporary Music, 1963 Jun. 5-Sep. 16; 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1959-1963; 3 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Hartt College of Music, 1961 Jul. 21; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Hungarian Quartet, 1964; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Hutchings, Thomas D., 1966 Oct. 25; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - University of Illinois, 1966 Apr. 17; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - International Horn Society, 1977 Jan. 21-Apr. 8; 3 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Juilliard String Quartet, 1962-1967; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Koussevitzky Music Foundation, 1973-1978; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - League of Composers-ISCM, 1957-1977; 13 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Marsh, Peter, 1962 May 16; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Martha ?, no date; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - University of Michigan, 1964-1970; 3 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Monday Evening Concerts, 1964-1965; 7 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1977 Feb. 7; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - University of Now Mexico, 1964 May 28; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - New Music Concerts, 1959 Mar. 7; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Parnassus, 1975-1977; 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Penn Contemporary Players, 1968 Oct. 1; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia Composers' Forum, 1967 Jun. 20; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Princeton Chamber Players, 1963-194; 8 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Taub, Robert, 1978 Apr. 13; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Tulane University, 1964 Jun. 15; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Westdeutscher Rundfunk, 1957 May 22; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Wintle, Christopher, no year Jun. 17; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Yale University School of Music, 1960 Sep. 30; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Universities, II.F
    - Columbia, Berkeley, Brandeis, II.F.1
      - Columbia, 1947-1956; 18 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Berkeley, 1952-1962; 29 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Brandeis, 1965-1972; 13 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Recommendations, II.F.2
      - By Seymour Shifrin, 1965-1977; 16 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Requests for recommendations, 1952-1977; 28 items. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Students, II.F.3
      - Letters from students, 1958-1975; 10 items. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Libraries, II.G
    - British Broadcasting Corp., 1965 Apr. 5; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Central Museum of Musical Culture, 1967; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Columbia University, 1974 Sep. 16; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Library of Congress, 1962-1974; 18 items. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Hamilton College, 1970 Aug. 8; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Free Library of Philadelphia, 1960 Jan. 29; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Queens College, 1972 Mar. 8-16; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Stanford University, 1969 Oct. 30; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, II.H
    - Concert arrangements, 1956-1978; 26 items. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Guest lectures, 1960-1979; 22 items. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Recordings and broadcasts, 1956-1978; 31 items. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Requests for biographical information and program notes, 1960-1980; 18 items. (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Programs, 1950-1981; Series III; .4' (1 box)
  This series contains programs from concerts including works by Shifrin and concerts given by his friends. The series is divided into two subseries. Subseries A (Concerts Including Shifrin Works) is arranged alphabetically by composition within the following subdivisions: Songs (and other vocal), Orchestral and Chamber Music, Keyboard Works, Choral Works, and More than one work. Subseries B (Concerts by Friends) is arranged alphabetically by performer or subject.
  - Concerts Including Shifrin Works, III.A
    - Songs (and other vocal)
      - Three songs, 1952-1954; 4 items. (Box 15, Folder 1)
        The Cat and the moon
        No second Troy
        Spring and fall
      - Satires of circumstance, 1965-1977; 13 items. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Orchestral and Chamber Music
      - Chamber symphony, 1964; 3 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Concert piece for solo violin, 1961-1971; 6 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Duets, violin, piano, 1976; 2 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - In eius memoriam, 1969-1978; 21 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - The Nick of time, 1978-1979; 13 items. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Pieces, orchestra, 1960-1981; 8 items. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Quartets, strings, no. 1, 1950-1963; 11 items. (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Quartets, strings, no. 2, 1963; 2 items. (Box 15, Folder 7)